I call The Honorable member Paul
Goldsmith uh thank you Mr Speaker um n
uh my pleasure to read the uh to speak
on the third reading of this the
insurance presedential supervision
Amendment Bill National is firmly
focused on responsibly managing the
government's finances and building a
more competitive and productive economy
and the insurance sector is a very
significant uh part of the economy
significant cost for he household
businesses uh and government as a whole
and those cost increases um uh those
costs have increased significantly in
New Zealand as a result of the
earthquakes uh we can't do much about
that but we can ensure uh that
government regulation effectively
balances the need for supervision of
this industry so as to protect uh policy
holders and the community as a whole and
the need to do that in a uh in a way
that doesn't add unnecessary costs uh
onto the industry and I think this bill
uh the insurance Prudential supervision
uh Act of 2010 uh did a a uh generally
effective and robust job in balancing
those two requirements uh but it's not
unexpected that some Provisions uh have
been identified as appropriate for
reform and indeed that is what is the
point of this bill and I'm glad to see
that we have widespread support across
the house for this legislation it does
not involve significant changes to the
existing policy uh and it is continued
uh expected to continue to benefit from
uh industry support uh certain
Provisions uh have can I just um
trespass on The house's time for a
moment have been identified as being too
onerous in the circumstances where
policy holders are not expected to gain
material benefits or additional
protection uh even if the insurer
complies with the requirements uh and so
uh those elements have been identified
and this bill will allow The Reserve
Bank to exempt an insurer that is
running off its liabilities from the
requirement to have uh Current financial
strength rating often there will be
limited public benefit for an insurer to
hold a financial strength rating where
it is required uh to cease to enter into
new contracts of insurance and for
contracts of insurance that renew more
frequently than annually diso disclosure
in writing of the insurer's financial
strength rating to the policy holder
should be made on at least an annual
basis rather than on every renewal those
are the sorts of things that this bill
has been working on and it's all about
making sure that the uh IND the
insurance industry which is so important
to the health and competitiveness of the
New Zealand's economy is uh maintaining
its strength and on that basis Mr
Speaker I commend this bill to the house
thank
you I call The Honorable Clayton Co